Starring
Time of Honor
The Drop
Episode 1
ENGLAND 1941,THETRAINING CAMP
OF POLISH SABOTEURS
- Good morning, men!
- Good morning!
10 seconds late! As a reward,
ten additional rounds!
The first four, ten knee bends!
The rest...
assume the position!
Bobby is in a good mood today.
One... two...
- Will you manage Michał?
- Wanna bet?
- I'll take a bet.
- A vodka in Nowy Świat St.
- Is it a bet, Button?
- Don't call me “Button
- Eight, nine, ten!
- Second round.
Go! Go! And the next!
And the next one! Go! Go!
Higher!
Faster! Move it!
The next one! Go!
Go! Go! Go! Faster!
Go! Go! Go! Faster! Faster!
Stronger! Throw it stronger!
Go! Go! Go! Third round!
Go! Go! Go! The next one!
Let me remind you, that the most
important is the right hold.
Bring the hand down, hold the mouth
and cut!
- Bronek will show you.
- Yes, sir!
Hand, mouth, cut!
Very well! Next is Władek!
Good! Now Janek!
Hand, mouth, cut!
- Next is Michał!
- Father is coming!
Sergeant. I have to take my boys
immediately.
Yes, sir!
At ease! March off!
- Are we ﬂying?
- Yes.
- Finally!
- At last!
Get in, Button!
- Go!
- You did well.
Well, gentlemen!
See you in Poland!
POLAND,
THE NEIGHBORHOOD OF WARSAW
Everybody out!
Get out!
This is the end.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee...
Take care.
Oberscharfuhrer, I've got something
important to say!
- What?
- I need to see captain Martin Halbe
- from the Abwehr.
- What?
Take me to captain Martin Halbe
or else tomorrow you'll take my place.
Can you hear me?
Bring him over here.
Why do they take him away?
I won't explain anything.
Drive me to captain Martin Halbe.
You won't regret.
Take him to the car!
- Son of a bitch.
- They won't shoot.
Fire!
For Germans only.
Come in.
It's not Paris here. I thought
that actors have a better life.
- Did you bring it?
- What you like:
Swiss chocolate,
cold cuts from Otwock...
- No, thank you. Do you have it?
- of course.
Most real potassium cyanide.
Have you heard the news?
Our troops will be parachuted
from England to Warsaw.
They are to blow trains,
organize guerrillas in the forests.
Probably they killed Mr. Sym.
- Finally, something is happening.
- Here. As we agreed.
It's been a pleasure.
Maybe I'll become an artist, too?
- Go. Curfew begins soon.
- All right. I'm gone.
I commend myself to your memory.
MARCH 1941,
OVER THE ENGLISH CHANNEL
Can't believe tomorrow
we'll be in Warsaw.
I'll walk down Nowy Świat.
The most beautiful girls are there.
Tomorrow you'll be waiting
till they pick you up.
But at home.
I'm fed up with England.
Though English girls
are very hospitable.
- Can't see anything.
- It must be dark in Warsaw.
- Only water and water.
- Damn it.
I forgot my cigarettes.
Have you got any?
Władek probably has.
Thanks.
- Give me one, too.
- You're too young, Button.
- How do you call him?
- Button.
When he was a kid, I had to do
his buttons all the time.
- Very funny. Give me a fag.
- Doctors don't smoke.
- But students can.
- Mum asked me to take care of you.
- She asked me, too.
- You can't forbid me to smoke.
There's nothing about it
in the rules. Give me a fag.
You can forbid him to smoke
as his father.
- Surely, cavalry captain.
- I don't feel like smoking any more.
"FORBIDDEN FOR THE POLES"
- He said: Ryszkowski.
- When?
Two hours ago. Standartenfuhrer
Keller decided to check this.
That's why he called...
he invited you to come.
Major Halbe, do you remember me?
Leave us alone.
- Herr Ryszkowski.
- It's me. I see you were promoted.
- Do you still ride a horse?
- No I don't.
What a pity! You were
a great competitor.
You too...
- No, I don't smoke.
- I can't give it up.
You were very lucky today.
What's your offer?
You've quoted my name in front
of the firing squad.
Maybe you just didn't want
to finish this war in a stupid way.
As a hostage
killed for some actor's death.
- I wasn't involved in this.
- I know.
It's interesting.
- An officer of the intelligence...
- I'm not one anymore.
Since 1937, is that right?
Sit down.
I have an offer for you.
And our future contacts will depend
on your decision.
Stop!
- What are you doing?
- Are you blind?
- I'm drawing.
- Great.
You're sleeping all the time.
You'd better get ready.
- I'm always ready, dad.
- Dad.
Now you'll call father
“major"
Stop talking. Remember
to stick to me after the drop.
After the drop, brother,
I won't have to time for you.
- I have to visit my fiancées.
- What fiancées?
I don't know, from which to start.
Look.
- Pretty?
- What is this?
Hania and Zosia.
What are you doing?
Do you have
any other photos?
I do, cavalry captain.
Give it to me.
And you?
If you get caught with these photos,
this means a death sentence
for your friends?
- Haven't seen her since war began.
- Neither I saw mine.
- Give it to me.
- I'll do it myself.
Wandzia, are you still up?
Get some warm blanket.
This winter can't come to an end.
- A tone of coal costs 15 thousand!
- But I'm not cold.
Good. Look, I have a new client.
I got him through the caretaker.
- I can see.
- A nice man.
Educated, you know?
He even speaks a bit of Polish.
When I told him, my daughter was
an actor, he was very interested.
- I have to clean it by tomorrow.
- You were to take care
- of the Fishers' kids tonight.
- I just wanted to leave it here.
Here you are.
How do you feel?
It's been 3 years.
- If he was alive, you'd hear from him
- Trying to console me?
You're not the only one,
who lost someone in this war.
You have to live,
meet people, take up something.
Am Ito wash
the German pants?
If it weren't for those pants,
we would die of starvation.
- I know you're doing this for me
- You have a good job.
Your colleagues act.
Should I sign the volkslist,
as my new neighbors did?
- See you in the morning. Go to bed.
- Mum...
Forgive me.
Come in.
Heil Hitler.
Sit down, Martin. I've been
waiting for you.
- Is this Pole your man?
- No.
- How did he know your name?
- We met at a horse riding competition.
Before the war. He was a captain
of a Polish team.
Oh, intelligence.
We'll have him interrogated.
For the time being
treat him well. Until we check
if he is of any use for us.
- I gave him time till tomorrow.
- Since when does the Abwehr tell me,
- what I should do with my prisoners?
- Listen, Gerd.
I've been planning a big operation.
But I needed the right person.
It seems, I've just found him.
You can benefit from this, too.
More than you think.
Yes, it's Keller.
How come, he ﬂed?!
Wandzia it's me!
I've forgotten the keys.
- What is it?
- My daughter...
- She needs to be in hospital!
- What's happened?
She might have poisoned herself.
Why should I help you?
- What's the matter?
- The actor took a poison.
I beg you! We have to take her
to hospital.
Don't butt in. Let them solve
their Polish problems themselves.
Get dressed.
Thank you.
Room number 7.
Doctor!
A new patient has been brought in.
She was trying to poison herself.
It will be all right, you will see.
Good morning. What's the matter?
Doctor, please, save her.
- Are you the family?
- I'm her mother.
My neighbor has a car and a night
permit. He drove Wandzia here.
Hubert Jelonek. Nice to meet you.
- What has she taken?
- I don't know.
- I found this on the table.
- Sister, stomach irrigation.
Please, wait in the corridor.
Please, wait outside.
I had a dream about
St.Veronica.
She said,that Hitler
and the Soviets would be at war.
So, we are of the same opinion.
She said, the Soviets
would beat Hitler.
With what? The ﬂails?
Why? They must have some tanks
or cannons...
Yes, one hundred-person tanks.
One man is inside and the rest
is pushing it.
You should tell jokes more often.
Jesus Christ! Who is this?
Holy Mother...
- It's our boy...
- Stay here with him.
Quiet. Quiet.
Easy, easy.
Don't say anything.
I don't understand the people,
who make an attempt on their life.
She broke down, Mr. Jelonek.
- She couldn't hold on.
- What's the problem?
The war ended.
If you want to survive,
you have to side with the Germans.
But they are bustling about,
teasing them and even shooting.
Damn heroes.
She's all right.
But has to stay for the night.
- Oh, God..
- You see?
It wasn't cyanide... Someone
has swindled her.
Doctor!
You're needed
in room number 16...
- I'm going. Excuse me.
- Thank you.
Shit. Storm, that's all we needed!
Can you see anything?
No...
but we should already be
above Germany.
- How can you tell it?
- Cause it stinks.
- Something's wrong.
- We're changing the course.
- We must be turning back.
- Why? When we've gone so far?
- We've already turned back twice
- Be more positive.
I told you so.
If it's not a leak of patrol,
it is the weather.
Our pilots would do it!
Quiet!
He's safe. He was badly shot
in his lungs. Hardly survived.
- Where should we put him?
- Here.
- What am I to say at the round?
- That you know nothing about it.
I take the blame. You'll get his new
name and address.
What if there's a night inspection?
Pray this will not happen.
Cpt. Karol Ryszkowski, officer of the
Polish Military Intelligence Service.
Gifted, ambitious, intelligent.
He was quickly promoted.
- In 1937 dismissed.
- They let such an ace go?
- He started to drink heavily.
- So what? All the Poles drink.
It's a romantic story.
He was in love with an actor,
- but she left him for another man.
- Every actress is a bitch.
My lady is an actress.
I didn't mean German women.
There's more. He got into debt.
He tried to do shady dealings
on delivery of gas masks for the army
and he came a cropper.
He had a good reputation,
so it was covered up,
but he had to leave the army.
After that, we took
no interest in him.
How come he was
among these hostages?
This just came in. He was
arrested as StanislawJurewicz
during a street raid in Otwock,
where he lived with his sister.
- Is the sister alive?
- I doubt it.
She was taken out
to Auschwitz last year.
Come in!
The prisoner is here,
Herr Standartenfuhrer.
- Bring him in!
- Come in!
Thank you!
Good morning, Herr Ryszkowski.
Excuse me, Herr Jurewicz.
You didn't mention, that you dabble
in underground activity.
You had the whole night to think,
so let us hear it.
What would like to tell us?
We want hard facts.
Let us hear them!
Just say it.
I know nothing.
- Nothing?
- Nothing.
What a pity, you've just lost
your chance.
I really know nothing. I've just
started. And I'm a nobody.
They don't trust me. I've been
assigned to a receiving post
- and get only snatches of information.
- Hard facts.
- Farewell.
- I only know...
where the paradropping
from England is planned.
When?
It's coded in the afternoon
BBC broadcast.
- Where?
- Near Chojnowo.
Come in, please!
- May I?
- Who let you get dressed?
I don't want to occupy a bed.You have
much more serious cases here.
- How do you feel?
- Good, really. I will go home.
Sit down, please. I'll take
your blood pressure.
Doctor...thank you for everything.
Please, take my apologies.
- Apologize to your relatives.
- I don't have relatives.
And your mother?
It's not my business,
why you did it.
But these days you can lose life
everyday,
- so why not start respecting it?
- I have nothing to live for.
Why do you start every sentence
with “I”?
My fiancé died at the beginning
of the war.
When the war started I had a husband
and two suns. Now I'm alone.
Have they died?
I don't know. I haven't heard
from them.
But you think they are alive.
For the time being, I try to think
about those, who are alive.
My job is not as responsible as yours.
I'm an actress. I'm completely useless.
Again, this“I." It's war.
We are all fighting.
I'm no good.
This is how the Warsaw streets
look like today. It's Marszalkowska.
All the streets have German names.
Apart from the traditional means
of transport, like trains and trams,
there are now also barrows
and rickshaws.
- This means of transport is...
- What a torture.
- It's the tenth time we see it.
- You think you know everything?
You're dangerous.
This is ghetto, separated from
the rest of Warsaw with a high wall.
All of its inhabitants
have to wear bands
with a star of David
on their right arm.
Will they be issuing passes?
What do you need a pass for?
Where do you want to go?
I have to meet Jane.
- And what about Betty?
- Betty?
Betty is the past.
Jane has so incredible dimples
above her buttocks...
Such a thing I saw only
with Polish women,
but never with the English ones.
Quiet, please! I know your thoughts
are in Poland.
I know, it's boring,
- but this is so called...
- ...Consolidation of knowledge.
These are legal coins
and notes:
one zloty, two zlotys,
fifty zlotys,
100 zlotys, so called miller s wife
and 500 zlotys.
I've never had a miller's wife.
That's all for today.
See you tomorrow.
Lieutenant, reporting with an order
from the command-in-chief I
We are ﬂying!
See you, professor!
- Chojnow, isn't it?
- Yes.
- So, we've got them.
- This is my present for you.
I spoon-fed you with this drop.
- And what's your gain?
- I only want Ryszkowski.
He'sjust a small fry.
But soon, thanks to me, he will be
the most important person there.
What's this?
My technicians have spent all night
preparing this.
A masterpiece.
- A fake order of general Sikorski.
- Has Berlin given you a consent?
Trust me, soon you'll receive
the Iron Cross in Berlin.
Czeslaw Sienny, construction worker.
Repeat, please!
Czeslaw Sienny...
- construction worker.
- Good morning.
- How is your day? Any new arrivals?
- Yes. Here.
Czeslaw Sienny... What brings him
to our humble abode?
At work a metal bar perforated the lung
We've operated on him.
Sister, take off the dressing
from the wound.
I changed it this morning.
Before breakfast.
In spite of this, change
the dressing.
- I'm having a very heavy duty.
- How long
will you risk our patents life,
and the lives of all of us?
It's war. Other people are risking
their lives for you.
You are irresponsible,
you disregard my orders.
I won't let you do it.
Are you going to be shit scared
because of every damned Boche?
I'm not going to do it.
Anything else? I want to go.
From now on I forbid you hiding
the wounded in my ward.
- This is my official directive.
- And what if I refuse?
Marysia, please.
They'll take him as soon as they
find an accommodation for him.
Remember, nothing personal
and nothing English.
- I never get fashionable clothes.
- Your new IDs.
The first names aren't changed.
Krawczyk Czeslaw.
Markowski Jan.
Oleksinski Bronisław.
Rylski Władyslaw.
Bonecki Michal.
You have to take this as well.
Oh my.
We were to be paratroopers,
but get to be a Swiss bank.
Here you have some change.
And cyanide.
As usual, hide it in a collar.
Władek...
I'd rather hide a chewing gum.
Władek!
But I won't take my own life
by myself.
Notes and coins go to the belts.
This is London. Here's the news
from the front line.
Polish submarine ORP ”Sokół” set sail
for her first battle patrol.
- Now?
- Yesterday was the first air-raid
to strike Berlin. 130 bombers
took part in it.
Among them, two Polish squadrons -
No. 300, "Land of Masovia"
and No. 301, Polish Bomber Squadron -
'The Warsaw Protectors'!
We'll end with "The Lancers
arrived at my window”
- Is it this?
- Yes, it is.
Tonight there's going to be a drop.
Set out. The area has to be
surrounded within a radius of 10 km.
We wait for an operation for weeks,
and then get an airplane every day.
- You talk too much.
- I have no objective reservations.
- Say it in a normal way.
- I beg your pardon?
He speaks like some aristocrat.
- And what would you prefer?
- Something normal.
Otherwise, I'll jump in the sea.
- What are you doing, Wandzia?
- I'm walking.
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
Can I go out for a moment?
I have to register food cards.
Are you afraid, that I would
poison myself again? No, I won't.
Bronek wouldn't want this.
- Wandzia, maybe he is alive.
- No, he isn't.
He's gone.
Leave me alone, please.
How is it?
Conditions are great.
We'll probably jump today.
Don't be so glad. Who knows
what will happen above Germany.
- Władek, will open a vent then?
- What for?
I'll piss into Adolf's soup.
Herr Standartenfuhrer, 3 partisans
from the drop zone are dead,
6 arrested.The area
has been surrounded.
- Good. Show us these partisans.
- This way! Follow me, please!
Open up!
- Hold a light!
- A torch!
- Do your job.
- Yes, sir!
You probably overrate your
opponents, Martin.
Your plan seems like firing
a gun at sparrows.
We've been hit!
It's the engine!
We're nosediving.
They'll try to extinguish the fire!
Hold on, Button!
Hold on!
- What did he say?
- We'll manage!
Sure.
- We are ready!
- Set the fire!
Gentlemen...
we are in Poland.
Herr Standartenfuhrer, reporting
readiness for the action.
Thank you.
Pray this time none escapes,
for you know, what will happen to you.
Yes, sir!
They are ﬂying
See you down, gentlemen!
Subtitles: Bonaducci
Translation: Agata Deka